A Guide to Commission records of the Virginia Dept. of Education, 2008-2014
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Commission records of the Virginia Dept. of Education, 2008-2014
The Library of Virginia
53588
1.05 cubic feet (3 Boxes)
Virginia Dept. of Education
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated in 2020.
Historical Information
In 1992, Delegate William P. Robinson, Jr. introduced and the Virginia General Assembly enacted House Bill 997 to create the Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. Memorial Commission as a legislative study commission. n 1997, House Bill 2198 (Robinson), was enacted to elevate the Commission to permanent legislative commission status under the authority of the General Assembly. The Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. Memorial Commission was created to honor the memory and legacy of Dr. King, and to continue his work through educational, historical and cultural programs, public policy analysis, and public discourse on contemporary issues.
The Virginia Bicentennial of the American War of 1812 Commission was created in 2008 (HB 1391) to prepare for and commemorate the 200th anniversary of the war. The Commission was compsed of 12 members and was authorized to plan commemorative events and activities, encourage research to promote historical literacy and understanding of the war, and support organizations throughout the state as they plan commemorative events. A special nonreverting fund is established to support the Commission's activities. The Commission expired July 1, 2015.
Scope and Content
Commission records, 2008-2014, document the involvement of the Virginia Dept. of Education in the Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. Memorial Commission and the Virginia Bicentennial of the American War of 1812 Commission. Betsy Barton, History Specialist with the Dept. of Education, attended Commission meetings and collected these files, which include agendas, articles, brochures, correspondence, legislation, notes, planning documentation, promotional materials, and reports.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in original order.
Contents List
- Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. Memorial Commission, 2008-2012.
  - Commission meeting, 2008 Nov 12. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Commission meeting, 2008 Dec 16. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Commission meeting, 2012 Sept 17. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Commission meeting, 2012 Oct 23. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Commission meeting, 2012 Dec 4. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Town Hall meeting of the Special Subcommittee on the 50th Anniversary of Public School Closings in Virginia, 2010 Oct 4. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Abraham Lincoln Bicentennial Anniversary Subcommittee meeting, 2008 July 21. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Abraham Lincoln Bicentennial Anniversary Subcommittee meeting, 2008 Nov 12. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Abraham Lincoln Bicentennial Anniversary Subcommittee meeting, 2008 Dec 9. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Abraham Lincoln Bicentennial Anniversary Subcommittee meeting, 2008 Dec 16. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Abraham Lincoln Bicentennial Anniversary Subcommittee - Sesquicentennial of the Emancipation Proclamation Music Work Group meeting, 2012 Sept 14. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Abraham Lincoln Bicentennial Anniversary Subcommittee - Sesquicentennial of the Emancipation Proclamation Music Work Group meeting, 2012 Sept 17. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Abraham Lincoln Bicentennial Anniversary Subcommittee - Sesquicentennial of the Emancipation Proclamation Music Work Group meeting, 2012 Oct 23. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Abraham Lincoln Bicentennial Anniversary Subcommittee - Sesquicentennial of the Emancipation Proclamation Music Work Group meeting, 2012 Dec 4. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Brown v. Board of Education Scholarship Awards Committee - Special Subcommittee on the 50th Anniversary of Public School Closings in Virginia, 2009 July 14. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Brown v. Board of Education Scholarship Awards Committee - Special Subcommittee on the 50th Anniversary of Public School Closings in Virginia, 2009 Aug 21. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Brown v. Board of Education Scholarship Awards Committee - Special Subcommittee on the 50th Anniversary of Public School Closings in Virginia, 2009 Sept 16. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Brown v. Board of Education Scholarship Awards Committee - Special Subcommittee on the 50th Anniversary of Public School Closings in Virginia, 2009 Sept 23. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Brown v. Board of Education Scholarship Awards Committee - Special Subcommittee on the 50th Anniversary of Public School Closings in Virginia, 2009 Oct 14. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Brown v. Board of Education Scholarship Awards Committee - Special Subcommittee on the 50th Anniversary of Public School Closings in Virginia, 2009 Oct 20. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Brown v. Board of Education Scholarship Awards Committee - Special Subcommittee on the 50th Anniversary of Public School Closings in Virginia, 2012 Dec 4. (Box 2)
- Virginia Bicentennial of the American War of 1812 Commission, 2008-2014.
  - Commission meeting, 2008 Sept 30. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Commission meeting, 2008 Nov 24. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Commission meeting, 2008 Dec 18. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Commission meeting, 2009 June 17. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Commission meeting, 2009 Sept 24. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Commission meeting, 2010 Jan 10. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Commission meeting, 2010 July 27. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Commission meeting, 2010 Aug 17. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Commission meeting, 2010 Oct 19. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Commission meeting, 2010 Dec 8. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Commission meeting - Advisory Council, 2010 Dec 8. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Commission meeting, 2011 Feb 9. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Legacy Symposium, 2014 June 19-21. (Box 3, Folder 13)